<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[gridtest2]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[gridtest2]]></description>
        <link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 17:09:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="undefinedrss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Proportion vs. Scale ]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Proportion vs. Scale </h1><p> The space shuttle itself becomes very passive, or active, in the image depending on how these proportional relationships are presented. How can this be applied to the work you see yourself creating as an artist?

The digital tools we use give us incredible power over perception and focus, and the picture of the tilt-shifted space shuttle is a perfect example of that. I can utilize scale to shift the focus of a piece between two objects, or even affect the implications of a piece. Imagine if the weather-worn space shuttle in the post-apocalyptic photo was much, much smaller—made to look like an old toy left behind by a child instead of a monument left behind by an entire civilization. Perhaps the rider in that piece would have no reason to pause, therefore becoming the focus of the image instead of the shuttle. The grand and surreal implications of the image would be lost, only to be replaced with a somewhat boring wasteland. In my own work I can utilize scale much like these artists did: to shift the focus, alter the implications, even challenge the viewer to think differently based on what the composition entails. That’s a pretty vague explanation but how I utilize scale exactly in a piece of work depends on the content, of course. I may, for example, leverage scale in an unexpected way with our upcoming project in order to add some visual interest and shift the attention.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>undefinedproportion-vs-scale/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b808891c-645d-40e4-8c0d-02ba756ad3a1</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 17:09:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>